Patrick Brandenburg

Software engineer specializing in mobile robotics and simulation development. Project management experience in robotics, industrial, and aerospace applications. Comfortable handling multiple tasks at once and working in multidisciplinary teams. Computer vision hobbyist with interest in robotics applications in simulation and real-world applications.

Massachusetts brandenburg.patrick@gmail.com (201) 674-0638 github.com/pjbrandenburg linkedin.com/in/patrickbrandenburg

Professional Experience

Mobile Industrial Robots

North Reading, MA

Software Engineer

1/2022 – Present

- Key contributor to development of platform to simulate mobile robot fleet
- Create ROS packages and services to monitor and control robot instances in Webots simulation application
- Implement REST API calls from MiR robotics platform in simulation to accurately recreate real-world application scenarios
- Participate in design reviews with product leadership group to target key development goals
- Contribute to refactoring efforts using SOLID principles as guidelines

AutoGuide Mobile Robots

North Reading, MA 10/2018 – 12/2021

Project Engineer

- Contributed to important product documentation and testing related to safety
- compliance, platform specifications, and operational guidelines
 Managed new product introduction to support key customer applications
- Implemented vital engineering processes including change order process for both internal documentation and customer applications
- Managed debut customer installation of autonomous forklift platform
- Experienced in troubleshooting faults emanating from software, electrical, and hardware origins

GEA Mechanical Equipment US

Project Engineer

Northvale, NJ 6/2016 – 9/2018

- Product lifecycle management of 15-20 customer specific fluid separation packages, valued at up to \$1 million each, from conception to installation, in a fast-paced product development organization
- Lead multidisciplinary teams for the design of automated and pneumatic control systems integrating flow components and process requirements
- Created RFQ packages, develop design documentation packages, source vendors of electromechanical components, create and complete test plans

Chromalloy Gas Turbine

Product Manufacturing Engineer

Orangeburg, NY 12/2015 – 6/2016

- Communicated regularly and effectively with engineers from GE Aviation, Rolls-Royce, and their subsidiaries for new and existing product lines
- Collected and analyzed a variety of data to substantiate new product engineering processes and gain customer confidence
- Regularly performed root cause analysis for nonconforming process fallout in material review to relieve quality issues and improve process yield

PHT Aerospace

Pompton Plains, NJ

Design/Aerospace Engineer

7/2012 - 12/2015

- Designed mechanical aerospace components and subassemblies through reverse engineering, using SolidWorks 3D modeling, simulation, and analysis
- Modeled designs for safety, manufacturability, reliability, and testing in accordance with domestic and international standards

Education

Stevens Institute of Technology

Hoboken, NJ

MEng, Mechanical Engineering

Boston University College of Engineering Boston, MA

BS, Aerospace Engineering

5/2012

12/2015

Recent Coursework

Deep Learning with PyTorch

- Implemented commonly used activation functions, loss functions, and optimization techniques from scratch
- Learned and built state-of-the-art convolutional neural network architectures such as ResNet, VGG, and AlexNet
- Used PyTorch to build deep learning pipelines for object detection, segmentation, and image classification on 2D images and video
- Utilized common deep learning practices, such as transfer learning and encoding/decoding, along with the TensorBoard toolkit

OpenCV Computer Vision II

- Advanced image processing and manipulation using OpenCV
- Introduction to neural networks using Keras, Caffe, and DLib libraries
- Applications built include smile detection, text detection, and custom object detector using YOLO framework

OpenCV Computer Vision I

- Introduction to computer vision image processing with OpenCV
- Implemented common image and video transformation techniques

Relevant Skills

C++, C#, Python, PyTorch, OpenCV, Pandas, Numpy, Keras, Scikit-Learn, DLib, Linux, Git

Additional Skills

Microsoft Office Suite, Mac OS, SolidWorks, AutoCAD, TensorFlow, IPython and Jupyter Notebook, Anaconda Distribution, MatLab, PostreSQL, SQLite, R/RStudio, HTML, CSS, PTC CREO/ProENGINEER, ProE Mechanica, LaTeX, Simulink, SAP